ultimaker.com 2019-09-25

# Privacy and Cookie Policy

This is the privacy and cookie statement of Ultimaker B.V. ("Ultimaker" or "we"), headquartered in Utrecht, the Netherlands. Ultimaker processes, amongst others, data from (potential) customers, visitors of its website etc. When you use our services, you trust us with your information. This privacy statement (the "Privacy Statement") applies to the information you provided and describes how and why we process your personal data, what we collect, with whom we share information, how we secure it, how long we retain it, what your rights are, and the legality of processing your data. In addition, this Privacy Statement describes how we use cookies when you visit and use ultimaker.com (the "Website") and includes a section on your use of the Ultimaker account and the services provided by Ultimaker after you have logged in.

 _This Statement was last updated on April 12, 2019_

## When we use your personal data

Ultimaker may request you to provide certain personal data in case you:

  * download software or a white paper from our Website

  * request a service from Ultimaker

  * sign up for commercial communications; or

  * submit a contact request

Ultimaker may use personal data to:

  * improve and develop our products

  * perform contractual obligations or take pre-contractual measures

  * provide you with a requested service

  * get in touch with you upon your request

  * engage in (direct) marketing activities

  * engage in personalized communications and advertising (with your consent); and

  * improve and analyse the use of the Website

Where required, Ultimaker will request your permission to use your personal data. In other cases, Ultimaker may process your personal data for the following purposes:

  * for the performance of a contract with you or in order to take pre-contractual steps at your request

  * for compliance with a legal obligation to which Ultimaker is subject; or

  * for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by Ultimaker or by a third party

## When we share your personal data

### Third parties

Depending on your interactions with Ultimaker, Ultimaker may disclose your data to the following third parties:

  * the Ultimaker distributor and resellers in your territory, when you request a quotation

  * parties involved in performing an agreement entered into between Ultimaker and you or your company e.g. to service partners for on-site support

  * Ultimaker's affiliated entities

  * Ultimaker's external advisors

  * (potential) investors or parties interested in acquiring (a part of) Ultimaker's business; and

  * other third parties to whom Ultimaker is obliged or entitled to disclose the data by virtue of applicable law or by order of a court or other competent authority

### International transfers

Ultimaker will only transfer your data to countries outside the European Economic Area as long as it is required and used for its approved purpose. For these transfers we ensure that legally accepted  safeguards are in place to protect your personal data.

## Email marketing communications

If you opt in to receive email marketing communications from us, we keep you posted on Ultimaker's latest product announcements, software updates, and new relevant content published on our Website. Pixel tags are embedded in our newsletters, giving us insight whether an email has been opened or not. We may use this information to reduce or eliminate information in our communications.

In some of our email messages, we use a “click-through URL” linked to content on the Ultimaker Website. We track this click-through data to help us determine interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our customer communications. If you’d prefer not to be tracked in this way, do not click text or graphic links in the email messages.

You can also unsubscribe from future communications by clicking the "unsubscribe" button in such communications.

## Data retention, modification and deletion

We will only retain and process the data for the purpose you have provided it to us. You are free to modify any data you have provided to us. Upon a data request removal, all active user data is removed. However, your data can still be part of an encrypted database backup.

## Your rights

You have the legal right to:

  * request access to your personal data

  * request the rectification and erasure of your personal data

  * request a restriction of the processing of your personal data

  * submit a request for data portability

  * object to the processing of your personal data, especially where Ultimaker processes your personal data for marketing related profiling

  * withdraw your consent for the processing of your personal data at any time; and

  * lodge a complaint with the competent supervisory authority (Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens)

If you wish to exercise your rights, or do have any questions regarding privacy on the Website, please contact us at privacy@ultimaker.com. We will respond to your request as soon as we reasonably can and in no event later than 30 days from your request.

## How we secure your data

Ultimaker takes the protection of your data seriously and takes appropriate measures to prevent abuse, loss, alteration, unauthorized access and unauthorized changes. If you have the impression that your data is not properly protected or there are indications of abuse, please contact us at privacy@ultimaker.com

## Cookies and similar technologies

To ensure our Website is user-friendly, and in order to engage in advertising activities, we use cookies and similar techniques on our Website. In the paragraph regarding the Ultimaker account, a further description on the cookies we use on the Ultimaker account is set out.

### Why we use cookies

Cookies are small text files that are stored on your device when you use a website. Functional and technical cookies are necessary to enable you to use our Website, and to allow us to measure and improve the effectiveness and quality of our Website. We use cookies to analyze and optimize the user experience of the Website. With your consent, we may also use cookies to show recommendations and advertisements tailored to your interests, and to develop marketing campaigns for specific target groups.

### Marketing related profiling

When you accept the tracking cookies on the Website, we analyse your behaviour with our marketing tools, in order to provide tailored content to you. Related cookies are not placed without your explicit consent and can be deleted from your browser at any time, as described below.

### Browser settings

If you do not wish cookies to be stored on your device, you can adjust your browser or device settings. Depending on your browser you may adjust your settings in order to block certain types of cookies. If you refuse all cookies, some features of our Website may not function as intended. Please check the relevant link(s) below to get more info on how your browser settings can be adjusted and how the use of cookies can be managed:

  * Chrome

  * Firefox

  * Internet Explorer

  * Safari

### Functional and technical cookies

Functional cookies enable the Website to function properly.

Google Tag Manager
    Ultimaker uses Google Tag Manager to serve functional, analytical and marketing tags. It can also be used to serve the cookie consent dialog and makes sure only the right tags are used.
MyFonts Counter
    This font counter is necessary to display fonts used on the Website.

### Analytical cookies

Ultimaker uses cookies to collect statistical data about the use of the Website.

Google Analytics
    Ultimaker uses Google Analytics to analyze visitor behaviour on the Website by way of anonymized data.
Google Optimize
    Ultimaker uses Google Optimize for testing alternate versions of content on the website. Google Optimize uses analytical cookies to target content variants to a user and a content experiment cookie to determine how a user interacts with the content being tested.
Hotjar
    Ultimaker uses Hotjar to create heatmaps, record anonymized sessions, form analytics and survey functionality to help us improve the Website.

### Advertising cookies and other technologies

Advertising cookies and other technologies enable targeted advertising via the Website, and help Ultimaker to advertise on third party websites. Combining data generated through the use of cookies, Ultimaker is able to show personalised advertisements. These cookies and other technologies are only used with your consent.

DoubleClick
    This enables targeting ads based on what is relevant to a user, improving reporting on campaign performance, and avoiding showing ads already seen by a visitor. As an advertiser, Ultimaker can set how long and how often the ad will be shown in the browser.
Facebook Custom Audience
    This enables Ultimaker to find its existing audiences among people who are on Facebook (by importing our email lists) and create "lookalikes" (a set of people who are similar to the people currently engaging with our business).
Facebook Pixel
    This enables creating custom audiences for Ultimaker ads, measuring conversion rates and targeting people on Facebook with relevant ads.
Google Adwords Conversion
    This enables Ultimaker to determine how many users interact with its ads, which ads and ad groups are performing better and whether users complete the actions defined as conversions.
Google Adwords User Lists
    This enables remarketing and constructing targeted campaigns based on the standard audience types.
Google Dynamic Remarketing
    This enables showing visitors an ad with the specific product a visitor has previously viewed on the Website.
Eloqua
    Refer to the "Marketing related profiling" section in this Statement.
LinkedIn Ads
    This enables conversion tracking and remarketing.
LinkedIn Marketing Solutions
    This enables conversion tracking and remarketing.
Microsoft Bing Universal Event Tracking
    This enables conversion tracking and targeting audiences with remarketing lists. To customize your online experience on Microsoft websites, please visit: https://account.microsoft.com/privacy/ad-settings.
Outbrain Amplify
    This enables engaging in remarketing via Outbrain's content network.
Outbrain Pixel
    This enables tracking conversions and other events triggered after a user visited the Website after clicking the ad.
Twitter Advertising
    This enables displaying ads to Twitter users and remarket them based on user interests and devices.
Twitter Conversion Tracking
    Track conversions triggered after a user visited the Website after clicking a Twitter ad.

## Ultimaker account

### Purpose and how we use your data

By logging in to account.ultimaker.com you can create your own Ultimaker account and gain access to specific Ultimaker services. The Ultimaker account and specific Ultimaker services are governed by the Ultimaker Services Terms of Use.

### What we collect 

Your general personal information is required for the creation of an account. Remember, you can always edit your profile to update the personal information you provide to us.

During your interactions with us, we collect:

  * Access tokens and IP addresses from login attempts

  * User diagnostics

  * Printer information like print group identifiers, printer

  * statuses and print job statuses

  * Meta data from your prints e.g. temperature, used materials

  * Your Ultimaker Cura configuration data

### Cookies

In addition to the general paragraph set out above, the following applies in respect of the Ultimaker Account. We use functional and analytical cookies on account.ultimaker.com.

Google Tag Manager
    Ultimaker uses Google Tag Manager to serve functional, analytical and marketing tags. It can also be used to serve the cookie consent dialog and makes sure only the right tags are used.
Google Analytics
    Ultimaker uses Google Analytics to analyze visitor behaviour on the Website by way of anonymized data.
